Several concepts ago, I've mentioned that we needed to define
在几个部分之前 我提到
the action value function before talking
我们需要先定义动作值函数
about how the agent could search for an optimal policy,
然后再讨论智能体可以如何获得最优策略
and we will see most of the detail for a later lesson.
我们将在后续课程中详细讲解
The main idea is this.
主要概念是
The agent interacts with the environment.
智能体与环境互动
And from that interaction,
通过该互动
it estimates the optimal action value function.
估算出最优动作值函数
Then, the agent uses that value function to get the optimal policy.
然后智能体使用该值函数得出最优策略
So this might all seem quite strange,
一切听起来有点奇怪
but it will become much clearer in
但是在下节课 当你自己实现该流程时
the next lesson when you implement this process yourself.
就会更明白
So for now, please bear with me and let's further ignore
暂时先别管并忽略
the question of how the agent uses its experience to estimate the value function.
智能体如何根据经验估算值函数这一问题
In particular, let's assume it already knows the optimal action value function,
尤其是 我们假设它已经知道最优动作值函数
but it doesn't know the corresponding optimal policy.
但是不知道对应的最优策略
So how does it get the optimal policy?
它是如何获得最优策略的呢？
This is what we'll explore in this video.
我们将在本视频中探讨这一问题
So we already have
我们已经拥有最优动作值函数
the optimal action value function and you've seen some of the optimal policies already,
你已经见过一些最优策略
but I've removed those hints here,
但是我删掉了其中的提示
so let's try to reconstruct an optimal policy from the value function.
我们尝试根据值函数重构最优策略
It's possible to show that for each state,
可能的方法是 对于每个状态
we just need to pick the action that yields the highest expected return.
我们只需选择生成最高预期回报的动作
So beginning with the state in the top left corner,
从左上角的状态开始
the policy will go right instead of down since 2 is larger than zero.
策略是向右移动而不是向下 因为 2 大于 0
Moving right, we see two values of 1 and one value of 3.
向右移动后 我们看到两个 1 和一个 3
3 is the largest value into the policy, we'll go right here.
3 是其中最大的值 因此我们将向右移动
And we can continue in this way,
我们可以继续这一方式
always picking the action with the highest value.
始终选择值最高的动作
So 4 is greater than 2,
4 大于 2
5 is higher than 1 or 3.
5 大于 1 或 3
Next, 4 is the largest.
接下来 4 最大
We'll skip over the state with 3 values
我们将跳过三个值为 1 的状态
of 1 because it's not quite clear what to do here.
因为不太清楚这里该怎么办
But then 2 is larger than 0,
然后 2 大于 0
and 5 is larger than 1.
5 大于 1
So now back to the state with three values of 1.
回到三个值为 1 的状态
It turns out that to construct the optimal policy,
实际上 为了构建最优策略
we have our choice here.
这里需要作出选择
The agent could go up down or right and all three choices would yield optimal policies.
智能体可以向上 向下或向右 三个选择都会产生最优策略
So let's just say the policy decides to go right.
假设测试是决定向右移动
And just like that, we've arrived at
这样我们就得出了一个最优策略
an optimal policy and it's worth summarizing what we've noticed here.
总结下我们刚才采取的流程
If the agent has the optimal action value function,
如果智能体得出最优动作值函数
it can quickly obtain an optimal policy,
它就能够快速获得最优策略
which is the solution to the MDP that we're looking for.
也就是我们要寻找的 MDP 解决方案
This brings us to the question of how the agent could find the optimal value function.
这样就引出以下问题 智能体如何找到最优值函数
This is in fact what we'll explore for the remainder of this course.
实际上我们将在这门课程的后续部分探索这一问题